The Psychological Significance of "Bible" Stories Chapter 2 "Genesis" Chapter 1: Chaos and Order Jordan·B·Peterson
I think this time
I can finally tell some "Bible" stories
It's best to talk more
I said last time
I want to give this lecture as soon as possible
I want to make it as complete as possible
Of course the possibility of covering the entire Bible
very low
But we will definitely tell many major stories in the Bible
And its opening
This would be a good start
The Psychological Significance of "Bible" Stories Dr. Jordan B. Peterson Second Lecture May 23, 2017
If everything goes well
Maybe in autumn or next year
I will speak again
If everything goes well next year
But this is a long-term plan
All right
Then let's start
I talked about last week
A passage in the New Testament is from the Gospel of John
This passage is intended to echo the opening chapter of Genesis
This is a very important paragraph
I will emphasize it again
Because in the process of writing the Bible
The order of writing before and after is not one-way
Just like most books
Because if you write a book when you reach the end
Assuming you are a writer, you can adjust the opening part and so on
It looks linear on the surface
But it's not linear
As if you are God independent of time
This is your book, you can play with time anywhere
The person who put this book or several books together
Make full use of this advantage
Make this story
Makes this story full of strange echoes
It appears in many, many places
And this sentence is one of the main echoes in the book
At least from the perspective of Christian interpretation of the Bible
Of course it includes the New Testament
So there is a strange point
That is when God uses words at the beginning of time
The other element or power used to create a placeable order is Christ
This is a very strange view
This is not available
A word of "superstition" can prevaricate the past
Part of the reason is that it is so weird
It doesn’t even fit the definition of superstition
This is a dreamlike belief
I think many points in the Bible
Are all such dream-like views
The basis of our standard cognition
They form a cornerstone of our clear
Ideas can emerge from it
This is quite complicated
This view is so complicated
So much that it is still embedded in the dreamlike form
But it seems to be related to the primacy of consciousness
In my case this is about the structure of reality
One of the most important questions
Because whether it's a physicist
Or neurobiologists are arguing about this
Hinder people from obtaining a purely objective worldview
In my opinion it is consciousness
Consciousness has various strange properties
For example, if there is no consciousness, what constitutes
"Time" or at least "Duration"
This is not obvious
It’s hard to understand if you don’t have consciousness
What constitutes "being"
Things seem to be like this
Think about it if a movie is showing
But no one is watching it
I know it sounds similar to the view of "Tree in the Forest"
But it’s different from what I want to talk about
If the movie is showing but no one is watching
In what sense can you say that a movie is showing
Because the movie seems to refer to the experience of the movie
Not the objective element of the movie
The world has a little character
At least as a human being in this world
It depends on the consciousness of the world to exist
Of course you can take the consciousness out of the world
And then said if none of us exist
If you don’t realize this
The universe will still behave in the established way
But it depends on
What do you mean by "universe" when you say this
Because in a way
The subjective experience of reality creates reality
Or at least this is a way of looking at it
Since we are all addicted to our consciousness
Although it is painful because it defines our being
So it is not unreasonable to give it a metaphysical primacy
The depth of this view does not stop there because some physicists
And not an unknown physicist
But people like John Wheeler
He believes that in the process of transforming the chaotic potential of existence into reality
Consciousness plays an indispensable role
Wheeler did think so
He is dead now but he did
That consciousness plays an indispensable role
From a neurobiological point of view
From a scientific point of view
We don't understand consciousness
I think we don't know anything about it
We can’t use basic
Materialistic philosophy to understand it
I do not know why either
If you are a scientist it's frustrating
But as far as I know we are in understanding consciousness
No progress yet though
We have been trying to understand it for hundreds of years
Although psychologists in the past 50 years
And neurobiology etc.
Countless efforts have been devoted to scientifically understanding consciousness
In short I think this view is
God used Tao at the beginning of time
Extractable order from chaos
This is basically the correct way to understand it
In my opinion this is deeply connected with another point of view
As human beings
Is to meet some invisible potential chaos
We are obviously not omniscient
And we can't do whatever we want
But we will meet some invisible potential chaos
This is what we have been fighting with
But somehow
We can always give it form with our consciousness
This is how people behave
If you observe how they see themselves
This is how they behave
Because if you tell people similar
"You should give full play to your potential."
What you mean is
As long as someone participates in the process in a proper way
Can reach a height that has not yet been reached
Everyone can understand what you mean
When you say that
No one will treat it as an unsolved mystery
You will encounter situations full of potential in your life
When you encounter a situation full of potential
You usually feel very excited
Because what you see is what it can be
You see the future beckoning to you
As long as you can handle it properly
It can be what you want it to be
In a very basic way
Activated your nervous system
We even understand how this happened
Understand how the nervous system works
Because the system that mediates positive emotions
Is largely controlled by the neurochemical dopamine
Its roots can be traced back to the ancient hypothalamus
This is a very ancient and fundamental part of the brain
It will be valuable to potential or to accumulation
React to new possibilities
It responds to potential with active endeavour and participation
So we put the world into it as potential
And it seems that consciousness is leading all of this
So this view
This is in the first chapter of Genesis
Main points made
You can see these in mythology
Judging from the knowledge I have
The bottom of the mythical world
There are always beings composed of three causal elements
One of the elements is intangible potential
Interacting with it produces being
And it is usually given a feminine essence
I think that's because it's like
The source of growth
Something like this
It's actually more complicated but very close
The second element is some kind of explanatory structure
It must work hard to solve the invisible potential
I think Immanuel Kant mentioned this
When he criticized
When the idea that "all information comes from sensory data"
This is entirely an empirical point of view
When you encounter this world
Your cognitive structure has begun to take shape
This structure already exists in you
If there is no such a priori structure
You can't understand this invisible potential
And give it a structure
I think it
to some extent
Similar to the concept of "Holy Father"
I will try to go deeper
This concept means that all of us have
Something beyond all of us
It's deep structure, it's ancient evolution
And part of the cultural process
Roughly speaking, it gives us the ability to deal with invisible potential
And generate reality from it
Then there is the last element
This element seems to be consciousness itself
The inherent consciousness of the individual
So you not only have this explanatory structure
And this structure has the ability to act in this world
It’s like you are the spirit that gives life to the structure of the dead
Something like this
As far as I know, the unique concept of the Trinity in Christianity
Is basically the invisible potential in Christianity
Never given the status of a deity
The second concept is a priori explanatory structure
It is the result of our existence as living creatures since ancient times
The concept of this structure can be traced back to
How far away
Finally, the concept of consciousness
Consciousness is the tool of this structure
Consciousness interacts with the world and gives it reality
In my opinion it is Tao
This concept is the existence of the Father as a structure
There is the Son He is transcendent
This is the characteristic of consciousness itself
Then the words of the Son
This is the effective principle of turning chaos into order
As far as I am concerned, this is a subtle point
to some extent
At least phenomenologically accurate
Because you do have an explanatory structure
You can't understand anything without it
Your body is an explanatory structure
It’s about 3 billion years old
Crafted in the evolutionary process
You can't perceive anything without it
Experienced countless deaths
Struggle and tragedy produced you
You have the ability to deal with this
Watching the endless chaos around us
And transform it into a placeable order
Of course in the first few chapters of Genesis
Also hidden a point
A very amazing view
It's almost unbelievable
That is human beings
Was made in the image of God
Of course this is hard to understand
Part of the reason is that God in these chapters
With elements of polytheism
Although this element quickly
Developed into a unified monotheistic religion
But i still don't know
Why did people come up with this concept
Because I really don't think,
When we think of each other
Will immediately think of the word "near god"
The concept is that every human
No matter how weird they are
Or how sinful it is
They all have divinity
Need to be respected
It is in the process of creating an observable order from chaos
Played an indispensable or similar role
This is a big and strange crazy idea
However, we have carried it forward
And believe that this is the foundation of our legal system
I think it is the cornerstone of our legal system
The concept is "Everyone is equal before God"
Of course this view is really weird
Hard to understand
How could anyone come up with this idea
Because people are different in all aspects
Is so obvious that it can be said
The natural perspective of someone or a human being
Is extremely hierarchical
Some people at this level are so despicable
Can be considered worthless
Sick waste is generally erased
And all power is gathered in
In a small group of nobles at the top
But if you look
The development path of the concept of "individual sovereignty"
Obviously it is in the course of thousands of years
Gradually clarified
Then it is firmly fixed in the imagination
That is, every individual has some kind of transcendent value
What i want to tell you is
If we abandon this point of view, it will lead to destruction
If you take this view seriously
Actually you did that
Because you have proven
Otherwise you will not be law-abiding citizens
You put this idea into action
Every civilized person is like this
Then the problem is
Why on earth do you believe this
Assuming that what you do is what you believe
I think this is fundamentally
A good way to define belief
Such a view is
There are gods of tradition and structure
This is the Father who uses the Son
The Son is a more active force
And mainly the power of verbal expression
I think this is very interesting
Because it is not closely connected with thought
But closely linked to speech
I think the reason is
Speech has a deeper meaning than thought
I think part of the reason is
At least in principle, speech is an open voice
Speech is shaped by the existence of others
At least it will be like this over time
When you speak, your speech is
Come out with a causal element
It will also undergo criticism and cooperation and mutual shaping
Another point of view is
Will be brought out from the unbearable chaos
The cognitive process of embodied reality
It has a collective and public element
By the way this is also me
Some reasons for advocating freedom of speech
I claim it is the supreme right
Because i don't think
Although for example
Provided in the Canadian Human Rights Act
Every right has the same value
But this theory is stupid
Because a lot of rights are in
Complete equal status is simply impossible
The impossible
It simply doesn't work
Although this is the law
But I think a big mistake was made here
Because there is a kind of freedom of speech
The divine quality you can't escape
It is the source of everything
I do think dream
You can say that this dream is summarized in
In the story of Genesis
It is through dreams that we can dream
The idea that we now regard as "consciousness"
We spent a long time
To figure out the word "consciousness"
It's not obvious
Who would know that we have passed thousands of years
What kind of struggle has gone through
To be able to abstract things like "consciousness"
And how do we dramatically
Show it symbolically and dreamily
So that we can express the word clearly
And take it to a certain extent
It is very intricate
Mentioned in the "Gospel of John"
There is a manifestation of God
Or an element of God
Similar to a transcendent consciousness
It directly in a living way
Working with the deep potential of the world
This is phenomenologically accurate
I do think
We see our lives so
Because if you think about it, you will understand
We tend to think that when you see the world
You are facing the material world
But this is not how you behave
Your actions look like you are in a
A place full of potential is also in this potential place
You can really make a difference
This is also very strange
Because of the way we treat each other
As if we have the ability to
The eternal way brings new forms into the world
Because the way we treat each other is like
We all have free choice and free will
Maybe we don’t have one but it’s certain
Those based on "We have no free will"
The society established by this view
Are not running well
And those based on "we have free will"
The society established by this view
All seem to run much better
Besides, people will get angry at you
If you treat them as if they were
Automatic machine without free will
People will think
Bound like a slave
It’s like saying you don’t have autonomy over yourself
Even worse
You are not responsible for the choices you make
Say that someone is not responsible for their choice
Is an insult to the other party
You know you often
If you want to do this from a legal perspective
You have to make a defense like "weakened capacity"
You have mental illness and lack of intellectual function
Was stunned by something, brain injury, etc.
This is why you are not responsible for your actions
Otherwise out of partial respect for others
You will assume they are responsible for their actions
such as
If you do bad things
Then you have to take responsibility
But on the other hand
If you do good
Also your credit
This seems necessary because
I mean you really
I mean it’s better than
Anything you can imagine is annoying
For example, you worked so hard to do it well
A very valuable thing
In the end it was regarded as
It seems to be the result of falling from the sky
And the real choice you make
Has nothing to do with this
People will be hit hard by such things
Next i want
I know these things have caused a lot of controversy
Debates about free will
Arguments about the nature of consciousness
But i'm trying
Observe clearly how people behave
And how they want to be treated
And then trace back to these ancient views
See if there are some metaphysical connections
Well, this book starts like this
"In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth" (Genesis 1:1)
"The earth is empty and chaotic
"Darkness
"God's Spirit is running on the water" (Genesis 1:2)
It’s hard to say
A difficult narrative
Because I want to understand it correctly
You have to understand its behind-the-scenes story
There are many ancient stories in the Old Testament
Enriches the meaning of these verses
I can give you a brief summary
One of the implications of these verses
Although you can't tell
Because it's written in english
You have to look at the original language version
Of course I don’t understand its original language
So I have to use second-hand materials
Very sad but
The concepts of "emptiness and chaos" and "yuan"
You see this is related to a concept
That is "the bottomless potential"
For example, it is used to represent
The word "emptiness and chaos" sounds like
I’m sure I’m not sure about it.
The other is "tehom"
It's important to know this
Because of the word and
An earlier Mesopotamian word is related
That's Diamat
Diamat is a dragon-shaped creature symbolizing salt water
Diamatt’s husband is named "Abozu"
Diamatt and Abzu are some
Hug each other
This is Diamat and Abozu hugging each other
I would say that this is potential and order
Something like this or chaos and order
They hug each other
From the combination of chaos and order
The myth of ancient Mesopotamia was born
Namely "Enuma Elish"
A creature was born, a primitive god was born
Then as the creation proceeds
Finally humans are born
This is the hidden meaning of these opening verses
That is, God seems to face the unknown
He carved the unknown into pieces and made the world out of it
What he faced was like some kind of predatory reptile
Or something like a dragon or a snake
I think part of the reason for this is
This is a very profound and ancient concept that is
The translation here is quite complicated
This is part of the way humans create the world
We have gone beyond the boundaries of safe space
Say it is a safe space defined by trees and fire
We take the initiative to advance to the outside world
Came to the unknown territory that frightened us
We met and conquered the outside world
Like real animals
Mammoth snakes and various predators
It’s because we took the initiative and bravely participated
In the terrifying unknown domain
The world is born
This view is deeply hidden in
In the opening verse of "Genesis"
In my opinion this is a deep point
I think our brain is made up like this
This is what I want to study hard today
That is the ancient circuit used by our ancestors
It is used to process the space outside the explored space
The space that has been explored is the homeland
A major feature of the unknown territory is the promise
Because there are new things there
But at the same time full of danger
We are prey animals
Especially when we were very weak millions of years ago
We have to go out
Face extremely dangerous things
It can be said that there is
Is the courage of the father
This is a spirit of paternal courage
Allows us to conquer the unknown
And conquer the unknown and create an inhabitable order
No difference
And our cognitive faculties have reached
Enables us to make high-level abstractions
But the underlying biological structure has not changed
I think the following statement is not the slightest exaggeration
The loop you use
For example, when you are arguing with the one you love
Some fundamental things
You are working together to build the world around you
Create a space where you can live together
You are using the same loop
Just a more abstract version
The circuit we use and our ancient ancestors
The loop used when walking into the unknown itself is the same
Where they will encounter beast predators and unknown areas
This is the same loop
But we will use it abstractly
Instead of using it concretely
But of course it must be the same loop
Because evolution is a very conservative force
if not
I think this is why we can easily
Demonize our enemies because
The enemy makes us face
Things we don't want to see
So our first reaction is
Use snake detection circuits on them
This explains why we have almost
Ability to demonize others immediately
It's not for no reason
It's not trivial
First of all this is a very fast response
Secondly, this reaction has been running for a long, long time
One of the variants of the hero
And I will make a variant of a hero
Seen as fragments of a portrait of God
This variant is a heroic warrior who beheads the enemy
Of course this is not a hero
What a modern political correct environment should look like
We also know why
But this is still going to the cinema
Watch and admire this image
This is the most type of plot
There are almost two kinds of love and adventure
Most adventure genres are
The enemy is always lurking in some form
It can be a human or an alien
Then someone rose up to face it to maintain order
This kind of story is inescapable
If you haven't experienced it in your life
So when you’re playing video games, you’ve experienced
Also experienced when you watched a movie
When you are studying
It will make you unable to extricate yourself
Even if you are an atheist
And your only religion is "Star Wars"
It will still capture your imagination
When you line up for three days and rush into the theater
You behave like a religious fanatic
But at the same time you are claiming
He is an atheist in his own right
Okay, "Void Chaos" is so chaotic
And its exact meaning is definitely hard to understand
I can give another example
Explain that you are in your own life
How to experience the potential of this invisible chaos
It can even explain the order in which you are living
How can we dissolve in the above potential
In Dante’s Hell
When he outlines the levels of hell
Dante tried to explore in this picture
What constitutes evil
This is a psychology work he is thinking
Have all kinds of sinful behaviors
But the crimes are also divided into three, six or nine classes
The most evil crime is at the bottom
Dante believes that is betrayal
I think it’s because it makes
One of the things that people can co-exist peacefully for a long time is trust
And I would say that trust is a basic natural resource
For example, there are some great books
Have written about the economic utility of trust
In some societies
The default economic default is trust
These societies are easier to get rich
Even if natural resources are scarce in these societies
You can see for example
See what happened on eBay
I think it is a miracle
Because what should have happened on eBay is
You send me a piece of garbage
I'll sign you a bad check right
Then Yibei.com was closed.
this is not the truth
The default transaction on eBay is so honest
So that you can hire an agent at the beginning
I don't remember what they are called
Anyway, you can pay them a fee
So they can guarantee the transaction
So you won't send me garbage
I will indeed pay you
At the same time we pay a 10% commission to the guarantor
The default transaction is so honest
So that these things disappeared immediately
Roughly speaking, this means that all these frozen assets
The rubbish you pile up that others might want
They can be realized immediately
The only reason all this works
Is that people trust each other
Trust is an incredibly powerful economic force
It may be the most powerful economic force
In short, if you have a trust-based relationship with someone
Part of the reason is
Trust allows us to look directly at each other
Instead of running away screaming
I mean to say
If i believe you
Then I don’t have to think about how complicated you are
Because you are really complicated
Like a chimpanzee with a ghost
This is human
As long as you can do what you say
I can trust you
What you say can simplify you
You can trust me
What I said also simplified you
Then we can act like we know each other
Even if we don’t know anything about each other
But once trust is betrayed
All evil thoughts will be triggered
I suspect that everyone here
Have been betrayed more or less
If you are in love with someone
At the same time you trust each other
Then you have some specific assumptions about the past
Have some specific ideas for the present
Also have some specific ideas for the future
Everything is stable
Then you are like standing on the ground and chaos
Walking on thin ice
Chaos hide away
The sharks under the waves are also missing
You are safe you are on the lifeboat
But once that person betrays you
Like your intimate partner cheating
you caught me
Then you will think
Your situation was calm the first second
Because your worldview is still based on the premise of trust
And the next second is really a flick of a finger
Your surroundings are turned upside down
Not only your current situation has changed dramatically
You are no longer the same as before
Your future in a few years will be off track
All this certainty the strange certainty you put in
Can collapse into incredible complexity
If someone betrayed you you would think
Ok who the hell are you
Because you are not the one I thought
I thought I knew you
I don't know anything about you
I never really knew you
All the things we did together
It's not what I think
What happened is another thing you are another person
This means I am another person
Because I thought I knew the whole story
But obviously i don't know anything
I'm like a blind fool
Let a certain pervert
Or like someone who is too naive to survive
I know nothing about humans,
I don't know anything about myself
I don’t know where I am
I thought I got home but I didn’t
I thought I went back to my house but it was full of strangers
I don't know what to do tomorrow next week and next year
All these certainties can be embodied certainty
All collapse back to the potential it was born into
This is really appalling
From a mythological perspective
This is a journey to the underground world
This is worth knowing
Because in mythology
Journeys to the underground world are particularly common
For example, the Hobbit went out to find the dragon Smaug
To win gold, this is the journey of the underground world
The journey of the underground world is happening all the time
Modern people don’t understand what the underground world is
However, we have all been there and visited frequently
Every time we visit the underground world
It is the day when the stability of the world collapsed
This stability is at least partly established by our speech
Because some kind of snake appeared
This is another way of thinking about it
This is a very good way of thinking
Because no matter how you carefully create a place for your knees
There are always unconsidered places
There will always be unexpected surprises
For this to make you aware of the finite life and the passing of years
Even incurred a bloody disaster
This is the eternal state of life
This part is why I think
The story of Adam and Eve is a prototype story
This is because we do all live in the garden
Because of the existence of a garden within
Half structure and society half nature
This is the meaning of the garden
A garden is
Warm Land of Wonderland on Earth
The harbor of love
But here is also perilous
Make you precarious
I think the reason
This story is at the beginning of this group of books
Because it explains the eternal situation of mankind
We are always in this situation
We are in a garden
Or we are fascinated
But there will always be a snake in the garden
What’s worse is if there are snakes
Given the human nature, then we will definitely not do anything else
I will run to interact with this snake whenever I have a chance
The fact is
If you want someone to tinker with something
The best way is to tell them not to do this
Don't get involved with this thing
Of course you know it well
If you have teenagers or even children in your family
Or if you know something about yourself or your partner
What these stories are trying to express
You might describe it as an eternal transcendent reality
It’s like an experience shared by all mankind
This is the essential meaning of "prototype" proposed by Jung
You can say that we tend to think
What we see through our senses is real
Of course this is true
But the truth we see through our senses
Just the truth in the time frame we are in
What we see are things that can be touched and picked up
The tools we see are in essence
Is something useful to our activities all the time
We can't see the eternal structure
Especially the eternal abstract structure
We have to use imagination to imagine these things
This is what these stories do in a way
What they say is that there is some form of stability
They surpass our ability to observe
This is not unexpected
If we are scientists, we can realize this
Because we are always abstracting things that we cannot observe immediately
But there is still a metaphysical moral reality
Or phenomenological reality, they all have the same nature
That you can’t observe them through your senses in your life
But you can use your imagination to imagine these things
And sometimes what you imagine with your imagination
More real than you can see
For example, numbers are like this
Examples of this abound
I would say this is also a good way to look at fiction
Because of an excellent fictional work
More real than the stories derived from it
Otherwise it loses its lasting power
This is the condensed reality even though
In a sense it never "happens"
It depends on how you define "happened"
This is a pattern that is repeated in many different places in different variants
You can extract the central pattern from it
The pure model has never existed in any particular form
But you extract this pattern from all these templates
Means you have extracted some kind of truth
I think the story of Adam and Eve
We will discuss some of the details today
The story is unforgettable
Because it tells the essence of the human situation
It will always be true
I can give another simple example
People have a strong sense of guilt
Some people in social psychology think
Most people think they are better than others
But I cannot agree with this view
This is not what I have observed in life
Maybe because I am a clinical psychologist, I will be a bit biased
I may meet more than ordinary people
People who are clearly suffering
I don't agree with this view
Because you don’t have to study the lives of most people too deeply
You can discover something truly tragic
I'm not talking about the kind of tragedy you can complain about
I mean, for example, your mother has Alzheimer's disease
Like your confidant committed suicide
Another example is that your relative has cancer
Or maybe your child is seriously ill
There must be something wrong with you
Because almost everyone has at least one terrible trouble
If you didn't wait and see, there will be
This sense of being tragedy has always been with people
What's connected with it is in my experience
I rarely meet people who say
"Hey I'm doing my best."
"I'm so awesome I don't see any room for improvement."
If you have ever met such people, you would think they are narcissists
Then you are right
Most people don’t think so
They would feel they could have achieved
A state much better than the status quo
They are very keenly aware of their shortcomings
I don’t feel like I have become what I should be
This also happened in the story of Adam and Eve
When people have self-awareness
At least in my opinion
Once people become self-conscious, they are expelled from heaven
Then they entered history
In history there will be the pain of childbirth
Dominated by spouse
You have to work hard like crazy
You are different from other animals
Because you realize the future
You have to work
You must sacrifice the happiness of the present for the future
Never stop and you know you will die one day
You have to shoulder all these burdens
Again to me this is really
Is there anything more real than this
As far as I'm concerned, this is how it is
Unless you are so naive
There must be something in your life
Will resonate with these descriptions
Why i mean
We are such strange creatures
Because in a sense we don’t seem to be comfortable with being
The concept of "fallen" also expresses this
The existentialists say that people feel
In order to exist they have to pay off debts
Because their being is a sin to carelessly
Maybe this is because we are keenly aware
We must provide some valuable things to those around us
So they can
Tolerate us in our daily lives
But its depth is more than that
Humans seem to exist in a post-disaster world
This is exactly what is described in Genesis
This is interesting because
In the story of Adam and Eve
Two disasters essentially occurred
Disaster happened when Adam and Eve awakened
We will discuss this in detail
They have self-awareness since then
And realized that he was naked
"Their eyes opened."
This is the term used in the book
Opening your eyes essentially means
Increment of consciousness
Because for humans, the eyes are related to consciousness
Because we are highly visual animals
So the meaning of the metaphor "open your eyes"
Similar to the metaphor of "wake up"
Once Adam and Eve wake up
They realize that they are naked
The classic explanation for this is
It is related to sexual sin
I do not agree with this explanation
I think its meaning is not so
Although there are related elements
It's more like when you realize you are naked
Say so
If you dream of being naked on the stage in full view
This is not a spring dream
Unless you're a showy, right?
All you want to do is cover your body
And then escape this stage as soon as possible
Being naked under the public eye is to make everyone
Is to let the whole society's judgments focus on
Your obvious flaw
This makes people self-conscious
This is a real human state
This is in line with the five character models
Emotional instability related
But people don’t like this at all
They don’t like to expose their vulnerability and vitality to the crowd
This is one of the two great fears of people
One is social humiliation and the other is death
For example, if you have a typical agoraphobia
You will have these two fears at the same time
Because her patients are usually female
It’s easy to think she will be in a public place
Suffered a heart attack
Make a fool of yourself when you're dying
This is an excellent example of the two archetypal fears of mankind
to me
I said I would not understand the meaning of these stories beforehand
Look at these stories under the premise of
I think this attitude is correct
Because they are all mysteries
Everything about these stories is mysterious
The reason we have these stories is mysterious
What everyone here is doing at this moment is also mysterious
I mean to listen to the lecture
In the process of reading Jung's works
Carl Jung has great insights on this issue
Because he views these stories with a beginner's mindset
And assume there is something in it that you don’t understand
Even if they are the foundation of our civilization
From a historical perspective, there is no doubt
They traveled through the fog of time
He is not satisfied with certain views on religion
For example, Freud’s view that God is just a projection of the image of the Father
Or the Marxist view that religion is the opium of the people
If religion is the opium of the people
Then communism is the people’s methamphetamine
There is no doubt about this
You were betrayed by someone
You fall into the underground world where you doubt everything
Entering the underground world is not a joke
Because not only do you not know where you are from
And don't know who you are where you are going
This is bad enough
This is the underground world itself but it has a branch
Its worst extension is viewed from a metaphysical point of view
I think this is basically hell
If someone really makes you difficult
Especially if the person is malicious in doing so
If you are betrayed
Is the worst kind of betrayal
Then the betrayer is the one who really wants to hurt you
They are not stupid to betray you
But for some reason I want to kill you
Then you will fall into the underground world
It's also from then that you start to hold resentment
The grief gradually rises to kill the heart even worse
If people are fed up with betrayal
They will start to struggle with the usefulness of being
Maybe it will reach a sane person
Unwillingness to get involved
And will breed the fantasy of ultimate revenge
This is a terrifying situation
I think that's hell
This is why hell is always the outer edge of the underground world
If you get into a situation you don't know well
And the surroundings are no longer good for you
This is only one step away from complete confusion
Only one step away from complete confusion, anger and resentment
Then the next step is revenge
And where you are now
Just thinking about it can leave trauma
I have seen this in people many times
I think everyone just needs to substitute themselves
You can think of how this happened
I think everyone in this room has
Quite strong revenge fantasy
At least at a certain moment in life
And usually for plausible reasons
Being betrayed is by no means small, but it’s for sure
It will shake your belief in being
But if the faith is so shaken that it makes you resist the being itself
Then there is no cure, that's for sure
It can only make the already bad situation worse
"God said "Let there be light" and there is light" (Genesis 1:3)
"God sees light is good
"Just separate the light from the dark" (Genesis 1:4)
This is another basic separation of light and darkness
In a sense they are
The two basic elements of our conscious being
Because of course when there is light
We are sober and conscious
Because we are diurnal animals
We are sleeping when night falls
Our existence is bounded by light and darkness
When there is light, we will get up and be alert
Part of the reason is that we are highly visual animals
This is different from most animals
Because most animals use smell
And we use vision
We are very strange in this respect
Vision total and enlightenment clarification
The dawn of a new day and so on
Light created in a sense
Related to the emergence of conscious beings
And this again echoes the above concept
The specific wording used in this story is also important
Because the word used for God’s actions is “saying”
This is the use of "Tao"
Or the active element of structure
It creates order from chaos, which probably means
Like the structure of the spirit appeared
And created a basic boundary of experience
This is what is shown here
"Just separate the light from the dark" (Genesis 1:4)
"God calls light day and darkness night" (Genesis 1:5)
From this we can see that naming things is also very important
You can see this in Adam’s story later
Because the task God gave to Adam is to name the animals
It’s like animals before they have been named
Does not really exist to some extent
This implies that the authors of the Bible
Try to show the following fact
Our cognitive faculty and language ability
Related to the way we turn the potential of chaos into reality
Because before naming something
We can't master it
For example, this is why everyone has a name
Everything you encounter must have a name
Because before it had a name
It just looks like part of the blurred background
You can say it existed before it had a name
This is true
But it didn’t exist before it had a name.
Once you name something
Its essence has changed
You turn it into
No longer just something of potential
But at least it is becoming a reality
Turning into tools
In the first few chapters of the Bible
The act of naming appears repeatedly
The reason is
It continues to emphasize consciousness
The importance of conscious language and speech
Speech is an important way to distinguish us from animals
We have not made much progress in teaching animals to speak
Our biggest achievement so far is the parrot, right
African Grey Parrot
One of them has reached the language level of four years old
incredible
Because how big the brain of a parrot can be
Maybe it’s just that big and then this thing can talk
This shows how much we know about the brain
I know they are very small or something
But we try to teach chimps to speak
They may learn some sign language
Especially if you have been teaching since childhood
But they don’t have the language skills like ours
They will never be able to pass on this ability to future generations
And this is obviously the essence of truly mastering a certain ability
So as a human
We are using language skills to parse the world in a new way
Conceptualize the world in a new way
You can say we are like ants
Our insignificant planet
Is just on the edge of one of the billions of galaxies
What's happening here is meaningless to the universe
But this is an arbitrary assumption
We are very complicated
No matter what happens on this planet
Are all related to conscious reality
As far as we know the change of consciousness
Probably the most important thing that happens in all places
There is no reason to think that consciousness is a trivial phenomenon
It took your brain 3.5 billion years to develop to where it is now
Humans are strange creatures
Feel free to browse on Youtube
Those crazy kids climbed onto the crane and
What is it called parkour?
Simply incredible
Humans are really crazy animals
We are almost omnipotent
I am very reluctant to write what is recorded in the Bible
The consciousness shift described in the early stories
Regarded as insignificant things in the universe
I don't think so and it's not obvious
Even if they are insignificant in the universe
Whatever the meaning of this sentence
What to say "The stone doesn't care what you think"
The question is who cares what the stone thinks
First they don’t think
What do they have to do with this
Even if these are insignificant to the universe
I have doubts about this
This is not insignificant to you
Because your consciousness is quality and meaningful
Take Heidegger as an example, the work of this philosopher
The impact on me is hindsight
Because I recreated some of the things he talked about in the 1930s
And I didn’t know him deeply at that time
Heidegger has a view
The basic element of humanity and human phenomenology is caring
He said this is the basic essence of your being
You have concerns about things
Whether negatively or positively
Don't worry about something or hate it
This behavior still involves concern
Even if the universe itself
Our existence is neutral and we are not like this
We are the only conscious in the known
So we’d better follow this logic
No reason to go
I can't help thinking
People are constantly trying to degrade the essence of their consciousness
This behavior has a dark side
I am studying psychoanalysis
I always think like this
First of all it doesn’t matter if you as a being
Then you don't have to do anything
This is an excellent reason to completely shirk responsibility
This really made me understand something
Because of those who are determined to revenge and harbor resentment
Always looking for an excuse
To show that they are not responsible for anything
Plus, "irresponsibility" makes people a lot easier
The idea that "consciousness is trivial"
Will immediately lead you into this astray
So I remain skeptical of this statement
I also think that behind this idea
Is a deep hatred of human nature
I sometimes read the comments on my YouTube channel
I often feel annoyed
Because i have heard
For example, some ignorant environmentalists will say such things
"If there were no humans on this planet, it would be better"
You can't say such things
If you hear yourself say something like this
You should go to the monastery and stay silent for three years
Blush every ten minutes
Until you learned your lesson
You can't say anything more cruel and inhumane than this
You take it for granted
Show your care for the world
"If there were no human beings"
Okay, let's line them up
Shoot with a machine gun
This is really disgusting and appalling
There is a hatred of human nature at the bottom of this view
You can understand why this kind of people say that
Because we always mess up
Not make up for the fault
We raped the rainforest and so on
But I do have sympathy for people
Although we have committed numerous atrocities against nature
But nature will return it all
It’s good to keep this in mind
Many things we do are trying to survive
At the same time suffer relatively least pain
We always try our best
Do it as quickly as possible
It's not easy
Our lives are so many and complicated
One more thing is
If you only observe people a little deeper
This is always a miracle to me
If you talk to someone, they are doing their duty
Maybe they did a great job
Such as nurses working in the emergency room
My goodness you have a responsibility
Maybe they work in a palliative care facility
If you talk to them, you will find
They also have four
The serious problem I mentioned before
They may all have diabetes
But they still get up early
Caring for dying patients
Oh my god
People deserve some respect
Just because they keep working hard
Don't make this world worse
Even if they also suffer from all kinds of
Troubled by endless tragedy
For this we should all show some sympathy for the same kind
We are not all gluttonous greedy monsters
I just want to swallow everything we pass
The truth is more complicated than this
well, let's get back to business
We continue to see the next part
"God said, "There must be air between the waters
""Turn water up and down"" (Genesis 1:6)
"God creates air
"The water below the air
"The water above the air is separated
"That's how it was done" (Genesis 1:7)
"God calls the air sky
"There is evening and morning is the second day" (Genesis 1:8)
To understand these because
None of this makes sense
I think I mentioned some
The world being created
In this particular description
Is a phenomenological world
There is a disc on land
Because if you look around in a wilderness
You are on a land disk
This is obvious
Then there is a dome on top
It is more or less supported by mountains
The rain fell so there was water on the dome
Where else does the rain come from?
There is fresh water under the ground
You can find it by drilling down
There is still salt water around here
This is the world
This is an experience world
Because if you are a kid
Ran into the wilderness to observe the world
It's like this
So this is the created world
There is something worth thinking about
This is also something Carl Jung is very interested in
These ancient descriptions
Half is the description of geography and experience based on observation
The other half is a psychological description
For example, Jung is also very interested in astrology
But mainly for psychological reasons
Obviously there are stars on the dome
Then when you observe these stars
You can imagine their shape
This will help you identify the direction
Because when you can see the shape of stars
You can recognize the constellations
So as to guide yourself at night
Then the constellations became gods
Then the gods became a scene
Drama comes from it
This is imagined projection
When Jung was analyzing astrology
He is actually analyzing people's psychology
Because he sees the narrative of astrology as
Human imagination projected into the universe
So when you are analyzing astrology, you are studying psychology
The same goes for these stories
The world they describe is not the natural world
Not as described by scientists
Because these people are not scientists
They don’t have the technology and tools needed
For them
This is the world
For us this is how they observe the world
So what we see is the way they observe the world
And many of the psychological activities
Our mental activity is largely
Are the same as them, so in this mentality
But it’s also interesting to understand its geographic matrix
So you can roughly understand these stories
I like this picture very much
Because from a psychological point of view this picture is very good
This is a very famous painting
It basically paints the world in our eyes
There is a dome inside, there are sun, moon and stars on the dome
If you look beyond the known domain
Entered the universe
They are like the movement of the planet's runner sphere
This is an eternal explorer
He is beyond his known realm
And is spying on the unknown
This is a psychological picture
Because you do know some things
Beyond this is the unknown
When you feel bold
You stretch out your feet to the unknown
Borders are everywhere
If you think you are brave
Want to do something for this world
Want to expand the boundaries you know
You will stick your head out of the known boundary
Take a look
The structure of the outside world no matter what it is
He is smart because he mostly stays in a safe place
I would say this is a good thing
Because if you just jump out
Then you might fall off the edge of the earth
I don't recommend this
Especially when you do it accidentally
For me, this is the reproduction of Taoist Taiji Diagram
Yangyu is here, this is your known domain
And the yin fish is the snake in the unknown
And the right position is exactly on the dividing line between the two
Because you seem to have a foot based on your known realm
It will give you a sense of security but it's a bit boring here
Because you know what's happening here
People don't act like this
They are not satisfied with safety
Dostoevsky in
It is also mentioned in "The Notes of the Basement"
This is a great book
I like his point of view
This is an early critique of the concept of political utopia
He said if you give everything people want
Eat nothing but cake
Do nothing except bath
Busy reproducing offspring all day
These are all his original words
The first thing they will do
But maybe after the first week
They will smash everything half-mad
Just to make some unexpected things happen
Then they have fun things to do
That's too right
From a utopian point of view
If you have all the things you want then you will
What will you become
What would you do
Are you just sitting on the sofa and watching TV
I mean you will become
I don't know what you will become
Just for a little entertainment you will immediately self-harm
And this is what people can do
We are not used to security and utopia
We can adapt to a certain degree of safety
Because we are fragile
But generally we all want to take a foot
Reach where we know nothing about it
Because there you will be vigilant
Energetic and nervous and coexist with it
I believe this I believe it is actually related to
The physiological hemisphere structure of the brain is related to
Because roughly speaking, the right brain is adapted to the unknown
And the left brain is too simplistic
But it’s still very useful. The left brain adapts to the known world.
The best place for you is between the two
And you can tell
This is amazing
It will tell you the real reality
Showing in front of you
You know when everything goes well
The feeling of being actively involved in this world?
You are in the right place at the right time
You stay alert, control the situation and participate in it
And to some extent lost the sense of time
The tragedy of life seems to fade
At this time you are at the boundary of safety and unknown
Your brain will send you a signal
Show that you are in the right position
It tells you what you do has meaning
This meaningful feeling is actually a neural signal
The power of the universe at that moment
Reach a harmonious balance in your being
This is why it feels so good
Otherwise, are there other possibilities?
Our brain can surpass our sight
It is for this purpose
The feeling of being involved
There is no reason to think that this is not a real signal
You can weaken it
You can say that the problem with just being in the known domain is
You don't know everything
This will become a problem in the future
The problem with being in the unknown is
You can't bear it
You will fall into panic
Because anything can happen there
And you can't cope
So you have to reconcile between these two things
You want to be safe enough
So that your physiology will not lose control
You also want to be in enough unknown
So that you can keep updating yourself
This is where the information flow is maximized
You know it well because this is
When you have a very speculative conversation with someone
When I don’t know how to read a book
When I can't help myself in a movie
Or what you did in your spare time
Or even your job itself
You will devote yourself to it
Because you are in the right place at the right time
Your entire nervous system is sending you signals to indicate this
I want to say that is where you should always stay
Of course you can’t because no one is perfect
But this seems to be reappearing heaven on earth
Because when it happened
You are in the right place at the right time
And follow some restrictions
We will talk about this later
Ok this is what this person is doing
And this seems to me similar to what God does
When he transforms the chaos of potential into a living being
And this is something that humans should put into practice
"God said, "The water of the world must gather in one place
""Show the dry land" and that's it" (Genesis 1:9)
"God calls dry land land
"The place where water gathers is called the sea
"God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:10)
Very interesting here too
Because a German named Goethe wrote a play
I keep calling this name
His name is John Wolfgang Goethe
I can't tell but the play he wrote is called "Faust"
He was very young when he wrote the first book
And I was very old when I wrote the second part
One of the characters is Mephistopheles
Mephistopheles is the devil
This demon will defend himself twice
I basically used the same words twice
I like this paragraph very much
Very profoundly speaking basically
Goethe’s Mephistopheles said he was the opponent of Tao
It's appropriate to say that
Because from the perspective of mythology
He represents the image of the snake in the Garden of Eden
We will explore this in depth later
But he has a very sophisticated philosophy
He's not just a messenger
He has a profound philosophy
His philosophy is very straightforward and convincing
It’s very convincing so people always get stuck in it
Much more often than they think
His philosophy is to look at the world around you
This is like Ivan Karamazov in "Brothers Karamazov"
Karamazov tried to dissuade his brother
Become a Christian monk
Mephistopheles said look at this world
Look at the world around you
It's a bloody place
Suffering is everywhere
All beings are weak and strong
Everyone treats each other inhumanely
The mess this time around is just
Brutal slaughter hall, endless hall of destruction
He said it would be much better if all this had never existed
This is a very interesting point and I do believe
I have seen it many times in people
When people fall into the abyss of despair
Especially when you are betrayed
And go astray into the underground world
You will have this idea
For example, your child is seriously ill
Maybe your whole family is in pain
Every family has hard-to-read sutras
You will have this idea
God who put this mess together
Is it really worth it
Is it really worth the pain?
Suicidal people will say
It's not worth it
Generally speaking before you commit suicide
You have been driven far off track
A man who is desperate will want to commit suicide
In this situation your answer would be
Being is so bad
Might as well have never existed
I think this is a very bad philosophy
I think if you really put it into practice
It just makes the things that drag you into despair worse
I can't understand this
If "Your desire to end your life is justified because of suffering"
Is a logical conclusion
Then its answer will not be "to create more suffering"
It doesn't make sense
According to my observation
Those who follow the Mephistopheles philosophy
Destined to make suffering worse
This caused another trace of worry
They just want to end their lives
I still want to get revenge at all costs
The conclusion I have always been
Say "Life shouldn't exist because it's too hard"
Just a cover
Their real motivation is
"Before I leave the world
"I want to do my best to make everyone suffer as much as possible."
If you read what caused the Columbine campus incident
What the murderer wrote
They will tell you
This is exactly what they concluded
And put it into practice
All in all
This passage says "God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:10)
I thought a lot about this
Because the problem is
Is something better than nothing
This is a good question
I thought of two things about this
One thing is that maybe it depends on how you are, right
There may be some ways of being to make the world reasonable
There are also other ways of being that make the world unbearable
I believe in the narrative that runs through the story of the Bible
It is precisely the dialogue between these two types of beings
The upbeat side of this story is
Being can't do without restriction and suffering
This can't be avoided
But there are some modes of being that might make this
Become not only tolerable
Even make it all better
This is a straight and narrow road
Is also a difficult path to follow
I think it is possible
I am not an optimistic person by nature
But this is what I got from thinking and reading
I think the really credible point
Well known
You can always make things worse
No one knows this
If things are like this then it must be vice versa, right
You must have a way to make things better
Obviously you have a way to mess things up
The question is whether you can make things better
In other words, can we have both fish and bear paws?
We can exist while enduring limitations and suffering
Transcend it with our mode of being
I think the "Bible" story
Maybe not just limited to the "Bible" story
But the "Bible" story is one of the best attempts of human imagination
To solve and answer this question
This is the purpose of the whole story
The first story is
Disaster caused by the collapse of self-consciousness
The beginning of human history
The rest of the story is
Ok we have entered history
Now we know we are going to die
Understand our mortal destiny
Aware of our own being
Is there a way of behavior
Can make this all reasonable
Or even make us win
And I want to say maybe this is something worth pursuing
This is also very interesting
Life is too short
There are still many difficult problems
You can't even tolerate your own shortcomings
I think
If you adopt a deep enough mode of existence
If you try to do
Then it's just a move to provoke a heavy burden
Is enough to rationalize the fact that you are limited to death and tragedy
I believe this I believe everyone agrees with this
Because if you observe people's behavior
You will find that they will look for someone they admire
They do respect others
This is a natural phenomenon that began in childhood
The children respect first and then imitate
We look up to those who can be brave
People who bear the burden of being
We call it deep in our hearts
Let us desire to imitate it and follow it
I think this is our deepest instinct
I think this is correct
Even if you are not so convinced of the positive
Because it’s more difficult to believe in the positive
You will also be convinced of the negative side
Some ways of being are so cruel and sinful
So that just reading it can leave a trauma
I think you still have a little soul left
You can't help being in front of this kind of story
Stay away from the cold
Alexander Solzhenitsyn
Maximum exposure
The wickedness of communist totalitarianism
He considered the Nuremberg Trials to be the most important event of the 20th century
This trial held after World War II showed
There are some behaviors that no one should commit
Regardless of their cultural background
Because these actions are crimes against humanity
There is universal evil
You can argue this
Someone did argue, but the problem is
If you argue this point then you have to say
It’s okay for this kind of thing to happen under certain conditions
That is to say in the concentration camp
Tortured children killed by poison gas
They were forced to separate from their parents
And other tragedies
None of this is a problem
This is just a point of view. This kind of thing simply happened.
Under certain conditions these are justifiable
There is no transcendental good and evil under this judgment
Practical is the last word
In my opinion this is not a correct conclusion
This is my opinion on the matter
This is also Solzhenitsyn’s conclusion on the Nuremberg trial
The concept of "it is good"
Even if you don't agree with this
Because it is not yet perfect
But I will still say this is your bounden duty
As a person involved in the creative process
At least act on the premise that it may be good
And do everything possible to push it
Partly because
Can you do anything better than this
What could be more rationalized than this
Do you exist
You know it well if you have any sense
If you can think clearly about it
This is what you want to see in other people
Maybe you are discouraged and cynical
But occasionally you see someone in
Throw a ray of light in the darkness
It will also refresh you and regain some hope
Maybe it can help you keep up
This is obviously a call to being
This is a confession from the depths of your soul
This is what you should be
Maybe by then
You have the opportunity to participate in charity
I still thought of
Let's talk later
"God said, "The earth will produce grass
"『With seed-bearing vegetables
"『The trees that bear fruit
"'Each one
"'The fruit is wrapped in the nucleus.' That's it." (Genesis 1:11)
"So there was grass
"And the vegetables that bear the seeds follow their own kind
"And the trees that bear fruit
"Every kind of fruit is covered with core
"God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:12)
"There is evening and morning
"It's the third day" (Genesis 1:13)
I like this picture
You see these old paintings are very interesting
If you observe here
Will see the halo around God's head
Will see the separation of day and darkness
God is on the dividing line between the two
That's the sun right
This is the halo halo is the sun
Sometimes the moon
Like a coin
The queen's head is on the coin
This is the queen on the moon
It's silver it's a symbol of value
Because the queen is the ruler
And the moon is also the ruler of the night sky
Of course gold refers to the sun
Gold is pure
Because it does not mix with other metals
It shines like the sun
So it has the characteristics of the sun
God also has the characteristics of the sun
Because no matter what he represents
All of them clarify things related to enlightenment with consciousness
The power of clarification and enlightenment
Exists on the boundary between these two phenomena
This is probably the meaning of this picture
This is a metaphor, this is a way to think about it
But it does suggest a deep insight again
That is, consciousness to some extent
Is an indispensable part of being
"God said, "There must be light bodies in the sky
"『It can be divided into day and night
""Marking and determining the age of the season"" (Genesis 1:14)
This paragraph is also very impressive
think about it
How long did our cave ancestors spend looking up at the night sky
Only then began to discover that there are repetitive patterns
Year after year so that they can mark the four seasons
I can't imagine how they figured it out
What a careful observation
I mean to say
We know that people figured it out a long time ago
Because there are those great monuments
For example, Stonehenge seems to be an observatory
The pyramid has the same function
People look up to the sky and try to understand
They are observing God
Because when you look up at the night sky
Will do almost the same thing
Try to explore the laws and order of the universe
These are all condensed in this short sentence
""Marking the seasons"" (Genesis 1:14)
It's weird to use stars as a guide
"『And shine in the sky
"'All Light on the Ground"
"That's how it was done" (Gen 1:15)
"So God made two great lights
"The big day
"Little Guan Ye
"Making stars again" (Genesis 1:16)
"Just put these lights in the sky
"All the light on the earth" (Genesis 1:17)
"Managing Day and Night" (Genesis 1:18)
So here is the concept of ruling power
There is a set of analogies
The two sides of the analogy are the ruler and the celestial body that illuminates the darkness
Basically like this
This is also very interesting
Because it took us a long time to reach an agreement on this point
Like I said last week
Agree on the concept of ruling power itself
And decide what constitutes legitimate power
It is not power
It is authority and ability
But not power
Not domination
It is more mature than these
Because the ideal ruler
Not in power
Power just means i can hurt you
But you can't fight back
This is not something you need in the ruler
Although it sometimes deteriorates like this
What you want is the kind of wisdom that illuminates the darkness
Link the ruler with the king of light
From a metaphorical point of view, this is completely reasonable
This is a very old concept
Is also another example of how we are rooted in dreams
"Just put these lights in the sky
"All the light on the earth" (Genesis 1:17)
"Manage Day and Night
"Separate light and dark
"God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:18)
Stressed again
Something is better than nothing
Maybe you can think about it like this
The declaration of the universe is like saying
Something is better than nothing
How did you know
I think the answer is
There is something instead of nothing
I know this cannot constitute an argument
But it is still a remarkable fact
But the strange thing is that this is the case
No one knows why
Maybe we should recognize this
See what we can do
See how we can make it better
Because we can do it
If we devote ourselves to it
And abandon our words of resentment and hatred
I know these emotions are not for no reason
Because people are suffering
Only God knows what being can become
If we do our best to invest in it
Only god knows
What can we conquer
What a magnificent city we can build
What can we relieve from the boundless sea of ​​suffering
I read about a person's deeds are amazing
I don't remember his name
But he found a kind of insect called Dracunculus guinea
Guinea worm is a terrible thing
You can check if you want
But let me tell you something
Although this stuff is nauseating
Guinea worm is a parasite found in Africa
It can go under your skin and it's still very long
Probably so long and thick
It will go under your leg and then go in
Maybe it will punch out a hole with its head
This is one of its cute habits
If you want to rip it out it will break
Otherwise you just need to pull it out and wait for it to die
But it's not like this, it will break
Many, many people have had this disease
You can’t imagine the tragic situation
You are the top one percent of society
And you live in North America, thank goodness
You don't want to think about this disease
Let alone this sickness
This man went to Africa and wiped out this ghost
Really great
in my opinion
Without the guinea worm, the planet has become much better
Although I'm preaching the extinction of the guinea worm
I'm still glad they are extinct
What that person thinks of is
We don't need this kind of thing
It makes sense
Nice job
He can think so when he dies
This world is a little better than when he fell to the ground
So well done
I think this is a good goal
When you are dying on the sickbed
You can look back on your life thinking
"The suffering in the world
"Because of my existence, a little bit less."
This is much better than the opposite
Because it's totally possible
For example, you are Stalin
You will make sure this world
Because of your existence
And added endless suffering
We fully know that people can do this
Many people spend their entire lives just for this reason
I can't help but see this as some kind of metaphysical evil
I think this is the right way to look at it
"There is evening and morning
"It's the fourth day" (Genesis 1:13)
In my case you can see the sun and the moon from this picture
I really think this is the moon
This is part of the Sistine Chapel
Part of the reason I tell these biblical stories is
Humanities have suffered severe damage
I think the culprit is still resentment and hatred
I don’t think you can comprehend the essence of the humanities
And the deep meaning
If you don’t understand the story of the Bible
Because they are
The dream in which the humanities was born
Unless you have the background knowledge of these dreams
Otherwise these profound knowledge
Won't open the door to you
Dante’s "Hell" is an example
Milton's "Paradise Lost"
Is also a masterpiece
Milton wrote this work
Because he wanted to rationalize God’s behavior towards people
What an ambition is this
He is very serious about it
He takes this issue seriously
This is a Mephistopheles question
"The business we are involved in is so hard
"Maybe we should retreat in the face of difficulties"
I think the whole world
Made this decision in the 1980s
We were deciding
Whether to start that end-time nuclear catastrophe
We almost succeeded several times
I think to some extent
The collective decision of the entire human race is
Instead of destroying the entire chessboard
We might as well continue this terrible game
Milton wrote "Paradise Lost" to
This is still a dream
Trying to explain the nature of being and evil
If you don’t understand the story behind
You can't crack the mystery
It's really a shame because it is so profound
It seems to me why you need something profound
The reason you need esoteric knowledge is
Life is a profound problem for everyone
I mean you can stay alone and act conservatively
Come on
I understand why you do this
But you still cannot escape the ultimate problem of life
It's there in front of everyone
It will appear at least at a certain moment in your life
You better go straight to it
Handle properly
Finally ignite the beacon of power
I think the humanities should teach wisdom
Because it is wisdom that enables you to face the tragedy of life calmly
I don't know how you think this is a bad idea
There will always be such a moment where your life is at stake
You can't panic all day long with tears on your face and on the verge of collapse
Useless to people around
This is not the right way
The correct approach in this situation
Is to become strong and reliable
I don’t think you can do this without wisdom
If you don't cheer up
Unknown to myself
Wisdom cannot be gained without self-knowledge
This is what history and humanities teach you
This is not optional
The phrase "people live not on food alone" is particularly important
This is where the problem lies
Look at these magnificent masterpieces
Michelangelo didn’t just conceive all this literally
He is a godsend
He is trying to find something
He wants to work hard to explore the mysteries of human civilization
I think this is why you see the image of "patriarchy" here
See consciousness and tradition in being itself
Cosmic role
It is like a spring breeze
Hundreds of millions of people from all directions, whether religious or not
Will come to Rome and walk into this small church to admire this painting
There is something that everyone wants to see
It is not only beauty
It transcends beauty
It is food for the soul
Everyone can realize this
Although they can't speak
"God said, "Water must breed more living things
"'There must be birds flying above the ground
""In the Sky"" (Genesis 1:20)
"God made big fish
"And all the living animals that breed in the water
"Everything
"And make all kinds of birds according to their kind
"God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:21)
"God blessed everything
"Say, "Many breeds
"『Full of water in the sea
"'Birds will also grow on the ground" (Genesis 1:22)
"There is evening and morning
"It's the fifth day" (Genesis 1:23)
"God said, "The earth will give birth to living things
"'Each one
"『Livestock, insects and beasts
"'Each according to its kind'
"That's how it was done" (Genesis 1:24)
"So God made a beast
"Everything
"Animals follow their kind
"All insects on the ground follow their own kind" (Genesis 1:25)
"Class" means "relative"
"Kindness" means "treat others like relatives"
Then "God sees it as good according to its kind" (Genesis 1:25)
Which repeats these two sentences over and over again
"God said"
To call existence into existence is "God said"
"God looks good."
This is a basic judgment on the nature of reality
Something happened during the conversion
In the process of transforming from the Old Testament to the New Testament
That is, God blessed the creation at the beginning of the story
And in the Old Testament
God is not easy to mess with, right
If you misbehave slightly, he will punish you
Mercilessly
He has an arbitrary character
So many modern people think
How can you believe in such a god
When i read this i think
People in the age of the Old Testament didn’t think so
They think you better be careful
Life is really hard, if you dare to go one step further
You will face an extinction
To some extent
God doesn't care if you agree with him
It doesn't matter at all
Obviously you don't agree
But you better be careful
Otherwise you will be in big trouble
There is great wisdom in this
Nietzsche admired the Old Testament as a literary work
He believes that the description of divinity
Shows the fundamental nature of being
It is extremely accurate in describing its arbitrary and cruel nature
Ethical code
Is a moral code that humans cannot understand
He thinks this is very realistic
I like this explanation
But the stories in the New Testament are also very interesting
Because a kind of obsession suddenly appeared in the New Testament
When you treat God you should assume that he is all good
This is weird
Because you look at the world around you
Is it really good?
Cancer and earthquake do not seem to be suitable
And the misfortunes that happened to the children
Obviously these are difficult to match the concept of a god of all goodness
But the implication is
If you act this way
More likely to achieve it
Almost what it means
In a sense
I think this is an act of courage and faith
You have to try to do this
Just like what God did at the beginning of the Bible
In fact, being is good
You can't see this because
You can see the bad side of everything
But this is not the point
This is a metaphysical preset
This is a decision about behavior
I will assume that beings are good and act accordingly
Carry forward
The implicit idea is
This is the best way to improve the situation
There is an element of bravery
I think to some extent
This is also reflected in the voluntary sacrifice of his life by Christ
His presupposition is
"I assume that God is good and act accordingly
"I will put it into practice until I die."
This becomes a divine pattern
I believe it contains wisdom because
During most of my struggle with these things
I tend to study its opposite
I am not studying good but evil
Because evil is more convincing
Especially after the 20th century
If you think that what happened in the 20th century is not evil
Then you must be blind
Some of them are cruel
I can't imagine unless you imagine
And this is actually part of the historical record
I think if there is such a bad thing
Then this also clearly shows
The opposite of these evil deeds also exists
Is the thing that is the furthest away from these evil consequences
This does not mean that we can say exactly what it is,
To some extent we are easier to grasp
The meaning of torture, destruction and injury
It is difficult to clearly define
How to act to achieve the opposite
But at least it means it exists
I saw this pattern in the New Testament
Show it in this fantastic way
what can be confirmed is
It's about willingly accepting the limited life
This is a poisoned apple, right
Everyone looks to the future
And see that you are limited
Everything you love is the same
It's hard to let this not shake your existence
As far as we know this is inextricable
But maybe you can change your attitude
You can say this is the price paid for being
And the heroic act is to accept it
And not reluctantly accept
You have to say "Okay I will be with this."
"I want to accept it
"And no matter what, I believe that being is good and act accordingly
"Next I will see what happens."
"God sees it as good" (Genesis 1:25)
This is a heroic move
This change in attitude is related to heroism
Even in terms of the idea that the world is good
Also a brave attitude
especially
The mountain of iron evidence makes this conclusion difficult to sustain
But in my case the other option is far worse
In this picture, God appears again with the sun behind him
He is connected with the consciousness of the sun
He is creating these weird and magical creatures
People say
"Think of God as an old man in the sky"
Quite primitive
And a much better idea is
"Much better" Oh my goodness
In short, they said that the more careful idea is
Treat the essence of divinity as something like an invisible spirit
But this is not obvious
Because like I already said
There is nothing more complicated than humans
"Divinity is a kind of at least and
The view of "things equally complex for humans"
In my opinion is quite reasonable
I know this is a metaphor
Although I don’t know to what extent it is a metaphor
But it is also a concrete manifestation
This is also a very interesting point
Because this becomes more and more obvious
When we try to make artificial intelligence
Hard to make
Non-figurative intelligence or consciousness
It cannot be some invisible spirit
I think this is why Christianity is so stressed
Resurrection at the end of time
There is a driving force
Makes the concept of "body" sublime
Not just spirit
Consciousness floating abstractly above the body
You can't simply remove
The heavy and material part of you
And throw it away like trash
You need to make your body sublime
This view is also related to
Treat God as human
As a wise man
Representational correlation
At least from a metaphorical point of view
I don't think you should wave your hand and say a word
"It's all primitive"
Because i don't think so
I don't think it is original at all
"God said, "We have to follow our image
""To create man in our way" (Genesis 1:26)
"Our" is used here
Because this part belongs to the "Priest Document"
I said that the Old Testament has several original sources
In the "Priest Literature", if I remember correctly, God is called "Elohim"
I may remember it wrong but it's harmless
This is because
In the background of this story
God is a plural existence
It seems that the emergence of monotheistic thought
Encountered numerous obstacles in the long river of time
Because there are multiple powers
The concept of "power of all powers"
It is people who have gone through many difficulties to figure it out
What is constant in the source of power
Like a kind of meta-power
But it's hard to figure out what it is
As far as I know this is reflected in
The process of transition from polytheism to monotheism
First know through observation
Some power can determine the fate of people
At least in part the power you obey is like this
Secondly, there is a certain commonality among these powers
You can express this commonality with the following concept
That is, the sun rises in the morning and fights against the darkness at night
This is related to consciousness and dominance
One of the simple-minded atheism troubles me
What I mean by simple-minded atheism is
The kind of superstition that treats these stories as simple
This is really ignorant
Because no matter what these stories represent
They are not just simple superstitions
They were not fabricated by a conspiracy of priests
Used to deceive the people
Although from time to time these stories will be used for this purpose
It is much more complicated than this
These stories have very old blood
Intertwined with various other stories
Wisdom germinated in it
I think the correct way to look at them is
Regard them as the birthplace of mature philosophical ideas
You have to rack your brains to interpret these stories
I have said before
I will try to be as rational as possible
To discuss these stories
Instead of resorting to any metaphysics
Unless it is absolutely necessary
However I don’t want to exclude
The possibility of metaphysical reality
Because I think it’s too early to draw this conclusion
But you must take these stories seriously
If you want to handle this problem correctly
You can't dismiss them casually
This is inappropriate
""We must follow our image" (Genesis 1:26)
This idea is very interesting
As i said it's hard to understand
How did humans come to
"We humble creatures are almost gods."
Such as Mesopotamians
And the Greeks think so
Humans are not close to gods
They are just the playthings of the gods
The gods take pleasure by torturing us
Love, hate, anger and other such powerful forces
We are just the playthings of the gods
There is no special divinity in us
In a way, the concept of "we share the divinity"
Is an amazing idea
I don't want to underestimate
Abstract out the difficulties experienced at this point
Or this idea
The utility of our current model of being
"'Let them manage the fish in the sea
"『Birds in the sky
"『The livestock on the ground and the whole land
""Combined with all the insects that crawled on the ground" (Genesis 1:26)
"God created man in his own image
"In his image
"Making male and female" (Genesis 1:27)
Very interesting here
Because "Genesis" contains more than one creative story
In this story
Men and women are basically created at the same time
Eve was extracted from Adam
We will talk about this
But not so here
Both sexes occur at the same time
They all bear the mark of divinity
It's egalitarian
Is also beyond reproach
It’s also incredibly advanced
This is how I look at this story
"God blessed them" (Genesis 1:28)
Yo this is pretty good
"Tell them again
"『You must grow many and fill the ground to govern this land
"『You must also manage the fish in the sea
"『Birds in the sky
""With all the living creatures in action on the earth"" (Genesis 1:28)
This painting shows the scene where God created Adam and Eve
They seem to be very happy about this whole thing
This painting is Michelangelo
The masterpiece in the Sistine Chapel
The hidden mystery
I mean you will be curious
This is a digression, I don’t know if this is credible
But it’s interesting, it’s also a credible form
What is god doing there
What the hell is this
There are some interesting answers
The following is one of them
There is a group of scientists about 20 years ago
To this structure in the painting
A precise analogy with the cross-section of the brain
Of course Michelangelo is
One of the first people to have a detailed anatomy
So they think
For some reason Michelangelo put God in his brain
In my opinion this seems to be related to an idea
That is in the concept of God no matter what it refers to
Can be analogous or metaphorical to
The structure of consciousness was born
I think we really underestimated
Unbelievable and unknown degree of consciousness
It looks like your base is completely physical
But you are conscious and self-conscious
And in a sense you can create the world just by observing
What this extraordinary consciousness depends on is
Something emerging from that material base
And we don't know anything about it
This thing is really extraordinary
You have heard a lot of scientific reductionism
But I want to tell you something interesting. This is also a digression
The man who found the DNA
I remember it was Watson
It's Watson and Crick
But I can’t remember which of them wrote this book
Anyway, one of them
I don't remember which one it is
He thinks DNA is so complicated
So that it must come from space
He doesn’t believe it can evolve on earth
Many people who are used as models for scientific reductionism
Actually the opposite
You will understand when you really read what they are saying
They are well aware of the limitations of their knowledge
DNA is really amazing
It is eternal matter
It has been around for a long time
We think we know it is very stupid
I want to say the same is true for the brain
We know nothing about these aspects
Just learned a little bit
So this picture is very interesting
Maybe Michelangelo is really bold enough to express this
It's totally possible
He has the guts to dissect the body
At that time this was risking his life
He basically depends on robbed bodies
I would say that he is not very politically correct
It's interesting
This picture is a different expression of the same idea
This picture is funny
I have to add it
I don’t know how many people here know this
This is a joke in the camp of atheists
May be initiated by Richard Dawkins
Maybe not him
He said he believes in flying pasta god monster
Is as reasonable as believing in God
By the way, this is the flying spaghetti monster
This painting is called "touched by his noodle-like appendages"
Not very mature but very funny
"God blessed them
"Tell them again
"『You must grow many and fill the ground to govern this land
"『You must also manage the fish in the sea
"『Birds in the sky
""With all the living creatures on earth" (Genesis 1:28)
"God said,'Look
"『I will cover all the vegetables that bear seeds on the ground
"'And all the pitted fruit on the tree
""I will give you all to make food" (Genesis 1:29)
"'As for the beasts on the ground and the birds in the sky
"『And all kinds of living things crawling on the ground
"'I will give them grass for food'
"That's how it was done" (Genesis 1:30)
"God looks at everything that he has made is very good
"There is evening and morning
"It's the sixth day" (Genesis 1:31)
"The heavens and the earth are all made together" (Genesis 2:1)
"By the seventh day the work of God’s creation has been completed
"On the seventh day he rested from all his work" (Genesis 2:2)
"God blessed the seventh day as a holy day
"Because on this day God rested from all his work of creation" (Genesis 2:3)
I also like this paragraph
I did a lot of consulting work
It should be said that it is training
Target people are quite successful
They are usually workaholics
The kind of person who works 80 hours a week nonstop
They are such people
One thing we always wanted to figure out was
How much work you should do
One answer is to work till death
Work to exhaustion
And this is not a good idea
Then you have to figure out why this is not a good idea
The answer should be like this
You don’t want to make the amount of work you are doing
Affect the amount of work you can still complete, right?
Because if you work like crazy for two weeks
And then had to lie in a hospital bed for a month
This is obviously counterproductive
You need to figure out how much work you can do diligently
Then how much stamina to recover
Enable you to re-engage in work
People have basically solved this problem
And gave it sacred approval
This is a way to think about it
That is, you can work hard for six days
No wonder because you have to work
But you have to take at least one day off in seven days
Otherwise you won't appreciate life
This is part of the reason
In addition, repeatability is even more important
One of the definitions of morality is
The ability to do something repeatedly
If something is properly structured in an ethical way
Then you can do it over and over again
Without causing any deterioration
It's kind of like a relationship
If the relationship is negotiated
You can continue to negotiate
Then you can have a lasting relationship
You can negotiate today, next week, next month, and next year
This relationship will last forever
And this point I want to say that people get this kind of wisdom
God knows how long it took
That is, people think of saying that even God has to take a break
Appreciate what is happening
Following this pattern is not bad for you
This is the truth that modern people should understand
Because even
We are rich by historical standards
But our ability to relax has not kept up
I think this is a burden for people
Okay, I’m going to talk about the concept of God’s attributes again
I talked a little bit last week but I want to review it again
I think it is worth mentioning
Because we want to figure out
When people outline these performances
What are they trying to express
We came to a conclusion before
That people try to take specific aspects of power
Abstract the essence of power
At the same time people try to connect it with consciousness
The "consciousness" referred to here gave birth to the being itself
Also people try
Connect consciousness with something of cosmic quality
Whatever it means
This is a statement that "consciousness has cosmic quality"
Instead of discovering that "consciousness has cosmic quality"
This statement is meant to point out
In a sense
Consciousness has the meaning of creation
This also means
It is also related to humans
This is a very interesting proposition
And I don’t think you can easily refute it
This is a very coherent argument
Although it only exists in metaphors
Again I want to revolve around the concept of God
Establish a framework for contact
Freud would also do this when interpreting dreams
Quite useful
If someone asks me the meaning of his dream
I will let them tell the whole dream
Then I asked them to repeat it sentence by sentence
When they say something contains an object
Or someone or something
I will ask them what this thing reminds you of
Or what this thing means to you
Or what does it remind you of
This is the Lenovo technique
Its premise is
Your memory works with associations
That's it when you daydream
You will jump between things like a conversation
You can extract an idea
It is located in the center of Lenovo Network
Association caused by it
You can concentrate on the meaning of this idea
Jung expanded this technique
He called it "enlarging" dreams
He thinks about narrative literature
Or mythological similarities
Can be connected with the narrative structure of this dream
I think this is very useful
Dream is an idea that is trying to be born
It is only partially expressed
If you discuss and enlarge it
You can speed it up and turn it into a clearer idea
And dreams are also
Because your brain and heart are trying
Poke one foot into the unknown
It's trying to explain what's in the unknown
And make it concrete
But this can't be done overnight
It can't directly use the potential
Transform into clear ideas
Must first dream of what is there through the dream
Project imagination
Find out what it might be
This will show up in the dream
If you analyze dreams
You can make it more clear
This is what we are going to do with the attributes of God
Representational structure
Assuming God is an abstract ideal
Conceived it largely for
Combine this ideal with
Separate from any particular avatar or ruler
The implication is
When the ruler becomes an ideal
Then the country will become Egypt in the Bible
Egypt in the Bible is a tyrannical country
I think there is an unbreakable point in the Old Testament
In order to figure this out, God knows how long it took people
I.e. if you transform...
If you confuse the concept of rulership with the current ruler
Then your culture will immediately degenerate into a totalitarian state
And petrochemical
This is fatal and then you will become a slave
Sooner or later the whole country will fall apart
No matter how magnificent it is
Once the ruler becomes the concrete embodiment of the ideal
That is, this person cannot be
When distinguished from the ideal divine concept
Then this society will be inevitable
I think it's that simple
I think in the 20th century
We have witnessed too many lessons learned
And now we are witnessing the repeat of history
When the ruler becomes the ideal itself
The country will become Egypt in the Bible
And Egypt in the Bible is the prototype of tyranny
What is god like
From a Christian perspective
There are three elements
One seems to be related to tradition
The Father
This part is the concrete embodiment of human beings
This concept is very very old
Partly too
It is also the concrete embodiment of human tradition
It’s also a very old concept
It refers to the structure I said before
It is the structure from which consciousness arises
Enable us to deal with the unknown
Then there is an intermediary between the Father and Christ
The bird in the picture of the Holy Spirit
This is the more abstract Holy Spirit
I would say it might be Christian
The closest expression to the concept of "consciousness"
This invisible consciousness
Then there is the concept of "suffering individual"
The concept is very complicated
Have an old view
And I think this was originally a Jewish view
God's attributes
Omniscience and omnipotence
What is lacking
It's like the koan of Zen
This is a very interesting point
Because what does something like this lack
It lacks restrictions
All things lack restrictions
When I first encountered this point of view
I really feel empowered
Insight indeed
That is, "cannot achieve something" also has an advantage
Because it gives you something to do
I think this is one of the big reasons
If everything you want is at your fingertips
Then there is no story
It’s interesting that this happened to Superman
This cartoon character
In the 1980s
He can play the planet between his palms
He can bounce off the hydrogen bomb and be safe
Everyone is bored
What can you do to superman
You throw a hydrogen bomb on him
Then he just dusted and combed his hair
Then it's okay
The entire cartoon series is basically over
Because he is impeccable
No limit, no story
I think this is quite an amazing point
Part of the concept of christ
This is also a question that has puzzled me for a long time
I learned a lot from Jung
There is a point in Christianity
There is something like consciousness
It is eternal in a way
It runs through time
This is an abstract concept
But it lacks certain reality
Because it is not instantiated somewhere
It is not instantiated at an exact time and place in history
So the concept of the Son
The third person in the Trinity
Or one of the three persons in the Trinity
This concept is talking about tradition and consciousness
Must be embedded in a specific time and place in history
This is the embedded prototype
That’s "The Incarnation"
Perfect
He accepted the fate of mortal Shiren Bud
This is also the prototype story of each individual
Christianity has a strong character
I would say this is more obvious in the Orthodox Church
That is, the right way of life is
Tradition and spirit connected with consciousness
Put into practice in life
Put it into practice in your personal life
The way of practice should follow
The way Christ practiced in his life
This part means
Accept the tragic premise of existence
Part of the tragedy premise is betrayal
Betrayal from friends, family and country
There are also punishments for crimes you did not commit
Of course there are punishments for the crimes you committed
This punishment is sometimes a relief
This is the arbitrary nature of justice
Then there is finiteness
So this concept is your responsibility
And the way you set things right in the world
Are necessary prerequisites to accept these as beings
And still do good
I think this is a very powerful point
The world is weird
I have seen some very strange things in my life
One of them is
I have dealt with people who went astray
Get along with this kind of person
The interesting point is
They are almost surrounded by some kind of gravitational field
Of course I am making an analogy
Their worldview is so distorted and abnormal
So that once you contact them
Suddenly you are on stage in their drama
It is almost inevitable
They will try their best to be far-fetched
Make you the villain in their story
No matter what your intention is
Unless you have encountered something similar
Many of you may have encountered
Otherwise you don’t know how strong this gravity is
So some people can
Like a gravitational body
Twist everything around to fit their narrative
Adapt to their unfortunate and tragic narrative
I have seen the opposite
People do their best to forge ahead
They have a positive influence on the people around them
This cleans up everything around them in a profound way
I think this is an open question
If you can do your best to cheer up
To what extent can the small universe you live in can be reorganized
We all know if you do something wrong
Things can get really bad
There is no doubt about this
But vice versa
If you take care of yourself well
You will have a beneficial impact on your family
This will first be passed on from generation to generation
Will also benefit your group
We are in the same network
Our connection is not linear
Everyone is affecting each other
This is an open question
To what extent is expressed in action
"Being is good"
And "You can accept its limitations
The concept of "and still strive for good"
This is an open question
If you really choose to put it into practice
How far-reaching impact this will have on the structure of reality
As I said, the knowledge of my life
Made me believe that there are metaphysical elements in life
There are also rational and practical elements
I think sometimes they merge into one
I have seen this happen
We don’t understand the scope of virtue
We don’t understand what true virtue can bring
If we are careful and practical
The concept of "some divinity exists in the individual"
That is, the individual accepts the conditions of existence and still strives for good
I think this is a very interesting point of view
People have been thinking about this point quite seriously
I’ve thought about it for at least 2000, which also shows
This matter is indeed worth thinking about
This is the meaning of the concept of the Trinity
This painting also shows the same point of view
The interesting thing here is
You can see the Father here
He appeared in this strange thing
To be precise this is not the sky
You will often see these in old paintings
Is not what people believe in heaven
But as if the sky opened
There is a dimension beyond the sky
I want to show you this too
I just want to show that this is not only a Western concept
This is related to the mysterious experience
On the left is a Bodhisattva
It looks like he has a hat but it is not a hat
That is a large group of Bodhisattvas that lead to eternity
There is a hole in the sky
Like a hole into time
And all of this has survived in the long river of time
This is the eternal reappearance of the redemption archetype
The sky opened
You see it repeating again and again
This is basically the same point of view
On the right is the Pharmacist Tathagata who is a medical entity
Sitting cross-legged in the mandala
Mandala is similar to the embodiment of heaven
All the same concept
That is, reality opens to reveal the perfect image
This is a universal concept I think it represents
Metaphysical and physical
The possibility of unity in communication
In short, it is a concept like this
You need to keep in mind that some people have no doubt
Had a metaphysical and religious experience
This is true
You can induce it chemically and electrochemically
Many people with epilepsy have experienced epilepsy precursors
This experience is connected with divine enlightenment
For example, Dostoevsky had epilepsy
This is one of the reasons that made him a great writer
Dostoevsky was about to have a seizure
Will feel this way
He said it feels like the world is opening
He experienced an increasingly intense enlightenment
On the verge of reaching the essence of existence
Then he had a seizure
The subjective feeling is
There is too much knowledge in it that he cannot carry
you can say
That's just a nervous disorder, okay
But my goodness he is Dostoevsky
You can't take it lightly
This is basically the concept of the Trinity
Among them is the concept of the cross which is very interesting
The cross marks the center
It is a XX is the center of the world
It seems that X means the cathedral is in the center of the world
This is where you are
As a consciousness, you are the center of the world
Center of the world
Is a place full of pain and limitation of betrayal
This is the fact and the problem is
In view of this fact in view of the fact that you know it
So what should you do about this
The picture on the left
I think this is Goya's work
The hidden meaning of this work is
You should voluntarily accept all this
And move on
Go forward bravely with sincerity
This is the meaning of this concept
Your tradition supports you
This is why you need tradition
You need to be rooted in your tradition
Because without this
Without your father's support
The "father" here is both actual and metaphor
If there is no support behind you
Without your knowledge as a biological and cultural product
No depth of knowledge
You won't have the courage to do this
Because you don't know what you are and what you can be
You are a product of history
Sometimes students ask me why I study history
Because history is about you, that's why
History will tell you who you are
You can't tell who you are because of life
How can you figure out who you are
You need all this collective wisdom
All this dreamlike information
All these myths and legends
All these narrated stories
To tell you what you are
To surpass what you see in your eyes
You have been hurt and bullied
You have experienced 50 tragedies
You are humble and humble
You have all these problems
It makes it hard for you to see
The divinity hidden behind you
Unless you know the story of the heroes of the past
Understand the mystery of consciousness
I don't think you can have the courage
See yourself as that
Able to stand under the heavy burden of existence
And a person who walks forward with a heroic attitude
Of course this is part of the reason why I tell these bible stories
Now it’s half past nine, we’re over